麦琪:晚饭后我们就回来.你留着饭店的电话,
Maggie: Ok we'll be back right after lunch.
万一有什么事呢.
You have the number to the restaurant in case anything happens.
迈克:好,不用担心,如果本和开萝尔瞎闹,
Mike: Yeah, don't worry if Ben and carol act up I'll slap 'em around a
我会好好教训他们的.开个玩笑,爸爸.
little bit.Just kidding dad.
杰森:咱们走吧,亲爱的.
Jason: Let's go honey.
迈克:离婚了,天.
Mike: Divorced, boy.
本:对.
Ben: Yeah.
迈克:自从他开始惩罚我的那一天起,我就一直怀疑这人有是不是感情有过挫折.
Mike: You know ever since he started punishing me I've had my doubts about the man.
开萝尔:别说了,行么?可能只是一个误会.我真不敢相信,这可是我们的爸爸,这么好的一个人.
Carol: Now hold it, ok?This could be a mistake.I just can't believe this about our wonderful dad.
迈克:好了吧,开萝尔,证据都明摆着的!
Mike: Come on carol the evidence is right here!
本:对!
Ben: Yeah!
开萝尔:它可能是个大误会而已.
Carol: Well it could be a big mistake.
迈克:开萝尔,太明显了.
Mike: Carol, it's obvious
本:对!
Ben: Yeah!
开萝尔:什么太明显了?
Carol: What's obvious?
迈克:爸爸要离婚了.我们活着,
Mike: That dad's divorced.We're living a lie.
一直在说谎.如果爸爸说自己还另有真名,我都不会吃惊的.
You know I wouldn't be a bit surprised if dad wasn't his real name.
开萝尔:我真的,没法相信.
Carol: I just, I can't believe this.
尤其是,一直以来,
Especially after all the times he's told about their huge wedding and
他都在跟我们说他们的盛大的婚礼,当爷爷埃德拿着帐单的时候都晕倒了.
how grandpa Ed fainted when he got the bell.
本:还有啊,说那是妈妈一生中最幸福的一天.
Ben: And how it was the happiest day of mom's life.
迈克:还说过,爸爸如何向她祝酒,说她是……
Mike: And how dad toasted her and said that she was.
迈克和开萝尔:他想娶的唯一的女人.
Mike and Carol: The only woman he ever wanted to marry.
本:对.
Ben: Yeah.
迈克:如果他这些都只不过是一个谎话,那么……
Mike: I mean if he lied about this, then...
开萝尔:他以前是不是在说谎,我们不知道,他又没告诉过我们啊.
Carol: Well, we don't know that he lied, he just didn't tell us.
迈克:告不告诉都一样.
Mike: Same thing.
开萝尔:不完全是.
Carol: Not exactly
迈克:去年我跳学,那是骗人的,我没有告诉过他俩.
Mike: Well it was a lie last year when I cut school and didn't tell them.
开萝尔:不不,看,
Carol: No no, see that was different.
这就是不同.他俩问起你学校怎么样,你回答说非常好.
Now see, when they asked you how school was you said 'extremely pleasant.
迈克:确实非常好啊.
Mike: Which it was.
开萝尔:不,并非如此.
Carol: No, it wasn't.
迈克:确实非常好.
Mike: It was too.
开萝尔:不好.
Carol: It wasn't.
迈克:好.
Mike: It was.
开萝尔:不好.
Carol: Wasn't.
本:你想说什么?
Ben: What's your point?
迈克:我想说,如果爸爸以前对离婚守口如瓶,
Mike: My point is if dad kept this divorce such a big secret what else
那他说过的还有什么能让人相信呢?
didn't he tell us?
还有,我们怎么知道你告诉我们的是实话?
and how do we know that what he did tell us was the truth?
我们已经知道,
I mean we already know the wedding toast was a lie.
他的结婚祝词是假的.我们到底对这个人有多少了解?
so how well do we really know this man?
本:自从我还是孩子的时候我就认识他了.
Ben: I've known him since I was a kid.
开萝尔:迈克,你开始越扯越远了.
Carol: Mike, you're getting carried away
迈克:哦,是么?
Mike: Oh I am?
听好了,如果他从前结过婚,
Well listen to this,
那就是说,他还有另外一个妻子.
I think that if he was married before it probably means he had another wife.
开萝尔:真聪明.
Carol: Brilliant.
迈克:如果你还有一个妻子,那他可能还有其它孩子.
Mike: And if he had another wife it probably means that he had other kids.
本:哦,不.
Ben: Oh no.
迈克:很可能也住在长岛的某个地方.
Mike: And I wouldn't be a bit surprised if they were living somewhere
on long island.
本:爸爸不会跟自己的孩子住的太远的.
Ben: Man, dad wouldn't want to live far away from his kids.
开萝尔:什么孩子?
Carol: What kids?
本:就是他说他要理发去,实际上去看的那些孩子.
Ben: The ones he goes and visits when he says he's gonna get a haircut.
开萝尔:本.
Carol: Ben.
本:没有跟爸爸似的,总理发.
Ben: Nobody gets a haircut as often as dad.
迈克:这没错.
Mike: This is true.
开萝尔:迈克.
Carol: Mike.
本:我明白了.爸爸和他的那些孩子们玩,而他的那个妻子给他切头发!
Ben: I got it.Dad's other wife cuts his hair while he plays with his kids!
所以,他们不可能住得很远,我敢肯定就在这条街上.
So they couldn't live far away.I bet right on this street.
也许,我们去上学的时候,他们还回来家里呢,
Maybe they come over here when we're at school.And wear our clothes!
穿我们的衣服!玩我们的玩具!所以我的房间总是这么的乱!
And play with our stuff!That's why my room gets so messed up!
开萝尔:你疯了.还有你,迈克,你比他还不如.
Carol: You're crazy.And mike, you're worse.
我真不敢相信,我的血脉连着……就是如此!现在全想通了.是真的!
I mean I can't even believe I'm related
to...that's it!It all makes sense.It's true
迈克:什么?
Mike: What?
开萝尔:爸爸和他的前妻确实有孩子,至少一个.
Carol: Dad did have kids with his first wife.At least one.
他们离婚的时候,孩子归了他;当他又遇到妈妈的时候,
And when they split he kept that child:
他们起誓绝不告诉这孩子真相,
and when he met mom they swore an oath never to tell him that he was
---这就是,他只是我和本的同父异母兄弟.
the painfully slow half brother of me and Ben!
迈克:好,那小孩是谁?
Mike: So who is it?
迈克:啊,哈哈,看这个!
Mike: Ahh, hhaha look at this!
开萝尔:你找到了什么?
Carol: What did you find?
迈克:爸爸前妻的照片.
Mike: It's a picture of dad's first wife
迈克:让我看看.那,你怎么知道这是他的前妻的呢?
Carol: Let me see.Well how do you know it's his first wife?
迈克:我们找了一小时,只找到这个女人的照片.
Mike: It's the only woman's picture we found after an hour of looking.
开萝尔:所以?
Carol: So?
迈克:所以?看,还签了名儿呢.赠给我亲爱的,
Mike: So?Look at this, it's even signed.To my dear Jason.I know a place.
杰森.我知道一个地方.你的挚爱,派图拉.
Love, Petula.Ahhh.
开萝尔:你跟你爸爸一点儿都不像.
Carol: You sure don't look like your mother.
迈克:其它我什么都没说,我刚才只说了,我们必须找到关于这个女人的更多的材料.
Mike: Ok I just say, we gotta find out more about this woman.
开萝尔:其它还有什么地方找?
Carol: Well where else do we look?
迈克:如果我是爸爸,
Mike: Well you know,
我会把痛苦的往事给藏起来,
if I were dad and I wanted to hide the mementos of some tragic mistake,
我知道我会把这些东西藏在哪儿.
I know where I'd stash them.
开萝尔:哪儿?
Carol: Well where?
迈克:不许我们进的房间是哪一个?
Mike: What's the one room in this house that we're not allowed to hang out in?
开萝尔:他们俩的卧室.
Carol: Their bedroom.
迈克:还有呢?
Mike: The other one.
开萝尔:不会是爸爸的办公室吧.
Carol: Not dad's office.
迈克:现在,我们知道谁才是这家最聪明的人了.
Mike: Well, I guess we know who the smart one in the family is now.
本:嗨.
Ben: hi.
开萝尔;对,我们确实知道了.
Carol: Yeah, I guess we do know who the smart one in the family is.
麦琪:谢谢夸奖,可是我什么还都没找到呢.
Ben: Thanks, but I haven't found anything yet.
都是些病人的档案,而且,还上了锁.
Most of these are dad's patient files and they're locked.
开萝尔:哦,本!你把爸爸的东西散的都是黄油!
Carol: Oh Ben!You're getting peanut butter all over dad's stuff!
本:我会舔干净的.
Ben: So I'll lick it off.
开萝尔:本,你现在不吃不行么?
Carol: Ben, why are you eating that anyway?
本:我被遗弃的时候,会饿肚子的.
Ben: When I get bummed, I get hungry
开萝尔:我可不想搀和,因为这么做不对.
Carol: Well I don't want any part of this because it's wrong, okay?
我去搜他们的卧室.
I'm gonna go ransack their bedroom.
本:知道么,迈克?我一直在想.我觉得,爸爸根本就没离婚.
Ben: You know mike?I've been thinking.I don't think dad ever did get divorced.
迈克:没离?
Mike: No?
本:那本书只不过是个大闹剧,赠书给爸爸的全都是医生.
Ben: I think that book was all a big joke I mean the people that gave
那帮人有多愚,你也不是不知道.
it to him were all doctors.You know what nutty guys they are.
迈克:对,是我找到的他前妻的照片,
Mike: Yeah, but I found a picture of his first wife and get this,
还知道她的名字叫派图拉,她脸上画个颗假痣.
her name was petula and she had a fake mole painted on her face.
本:哇!
Ben: Wow!
迈克:对,我以前看到过!
Mike: Yeah, I've seen it!
本:我得再吃个三明治.
Ben: I need another sandwich.
迈克:嗨嗨嗨,这是什么?
Mike: Hey hey hey, what's this?
本:什么?
Ben: What?
迈克:哦,不!
Mike: Oh no!
本:什么?
Ben: What?
迈克:开萝尔,看我们找到了什么.
Mike: Carol, look what we found
开萝尔:什么?
Carol: What?
本:还有一个老婆.
Ben: Another stupid wife
开萝尔:这个女人有没有跟爸爸结婚,你又不知道.
Carol: You don't know this woman was married to dad.
迈克:那,他为什么藏着?
Mike: Then why did he hide it?
开萝尔:我不知道.不过,不能没有彻底调查就急着得出结论.
Carol: Well I don't know.I'm just saying that I don't want to jump to
any conclusions without a complete search
本:求求你了,开萝尔,别找了,呆会儿说不定你又找出个什么前妻出来!
Ben: Please carol, stop looking before you find any more wives!
开萝尔:迈克,你能不能过来帮帮我?
Carol: Mike, will you help me down with this box.
迈克:好的,爸爸从哪儿弄的这么多衣服?
Mike: Yeah, man where did dad get all of these clothes?
他会拿这么多衣服做什么用?
What's he doing with all these sweater vests?
本:是不是父亲节收的礼物啊,他数以百计的孩子们也会送的.
Ben: He probably gets father's day presents from his hundreds of other kids too.
迈克:嗨,看,
Mike: Hey look at this.My first issue.
这是妈妈在工作的起讫时间.
This is when from when mom started working at Newsweek.
开萝尔:哦,哇,她从1969年就开始积攒这个了.
Carol: Oh wow, she saved this from 1969.
Ben: Mom saves everything.Cards, letters, mike's first C
开萝尔:有件事情非常蹊跷.年份:1969,
Carol: Guys, guys, there's something very strange about this.Year: 1969.
这一年,爸爸应该在菲尼克斯做实习生.
that was the year dad supposedly did his internship in phoenix.
迈克:所以?
Mike: So?
开萝尔:所以,爸爸,妈妈在此一年之前就结婚了.
Carol: So the second year of mom and dad's marriage.
本:那年,他俩住在房车公园,一天到晚吃的都是豆子.
Ben: The year they lived in the trailer park and ate beans all the time.
迈克:那又怎么了?
Mike: So what?
开萝尔:那,妈妈怎么能一面在纽约给上班,
Carol: So how could mom be in New York working for Newsweek and be in
一面在菲尼克斯吃豆子,啊?
phoenix eating beans at the same time, hmm?
本:我还得再吃个三明治.
Ben: I need another sandwich.
开萝尔:这儿还有其它什么发现?
Carol: What else is in here?
迈克:就一些平常的东西.婴儿的照片,压干的花,小孩儿手镯.
Mike: Just the usual stuff.Baby pictures, first flowers, a charm bracelet.
开萝尔:从前给妈妈的信.
Carol: An old letter to mom.
迈克:哦噢.念一念.
Mike: Ooh ooh.Read it.
开萝尔:不!怎么能这么做.
Carol: No!we shouldn't.
迈克:来,念啊.
Mike: Come on.
开萝尔:是爷爷埃德写的,
Carol: It's from Grandpa Ed,
亲爱的玛格丽特*凯瑟琳,过去的数周,
Dear Margaret Catherine in all the confusion of the past few weeks I haven't
我一直困惑不安,
found the time to tell you that your mom and I love you very much.
我一直找不出时间告诉你---你妈妈和我都非常地爱你.没有理由灰心失望,
There's no reason to lose heart just because that ex-husband of yours
因为你的前夫不值得你这么样.
turned out to be a lunkhead.
迈克:那就是说,妈妈也离过婚.好事,
Mike: So that means mom was divorced too.Good thing Ben wasn't in here.
本不在这儿.否则,他得把那家俱给吃了.
He'd be eating the furniture.
本:(打饱嗝)
Ben: (burp)
麦琪:嗨,孩子们.
Maggie: Hi guys.
孩子们:嗨.
Kids: Hi.
开萝尔:爸爸呢?
Carol: Where's dad?
麦琪:哦,我们分手了,下午分的.
Maggie: Oh, we split up.For the afternoon.
孩子们:哦.
Kids: Ohh.
麦琪:他把我放下,然后去理发了.
Maggie: He dropped me off and then went for a haircut.
本:啊------!
Ben: Argghhhh!
杰森:嗨,亲爱的.
Jason: Hi honey.
麦琪:嗨,我以为你正在理发呢.
Maggie: Hi, oh I thought you were getting a haircut?
杰森:我理完了.
Jason: I did.
麦琪:不像啊.
Maggie: It doesn't look like it.
杰森:肯定不像了,所以人家理发要得才贵啊.孩子们呢?
Jason: Of course it doesn't.That's why they charge so much.Where are the kids?
麦琪:哦,你们都坐在沙发上,一个挨一个.
Maggie: Oh well they're all sitting side-by-side on the couch.
杰森,这好怪啊.
Jason it's eerie.They aren't yelling.They aren't fighting.
他们也不吵,也不闹,甚至也不看电视.
They aren't even watching TV.
杰森:这难道是坏事么?你,兰博.
Jason: This is a bad thing?Yo Rambo.
本:嗨,给你剪头的那人叫什么?
Ben: Hi, what's the name of your barber?
杰森:呃,琳达.
Jason: Uhh, Linda.
本:不是派图拉,有个假痣的那个?
Ben: Not petula with a fake mole.
杰森:不是.
Jason: No.
本:那就对了.
Ben: Yeah right.
麦琪:本,不要吃太多了,会没胃口的.
Maggie: Ben, don't eat too much.You'll spoil your appetite.
本:哦,肯定不可能.
Ben: Oh, not a chance.
开萝尔:我们为什么不直截了当问他们离婚的事儿呢?
Carol: Well why don't we just ask them about these divorces?
迈克:开萝尔,我们已有的了解,
Mike: Carol, after everything we've learned here do you really think they're
你会相信他们会告诉我们真相么?
going to tell us the truth?
开萝尔:我们总得做点什么吧,要不待会儿,
Carol: Well we gotta do something before Ben ends up with a harpoon sticking
本就吃炸了.
out of him.
迈克:听好了,我想好了一个主意.
Mike: Ok listen, guys, I've formulated a plan.
开萝尔:什么?
Carol: What?
迈克:我们做错事的时候,
Mike: Now when we do something wrong,
如果爸爸妈妈不太清楚事情的原委,
only mom and dad don't know quite what it is,
他们会跟我们谈话,引诱我们多说.
they usually get us into this conversation about other junk just to trick
那现在我们以其人之道还制其人之身.
us into saying too much so let's just do that to them.
开萝尔:他们可从来没有那个样子对我.
Carol: They never do that to me.
迈克:开萝尔,那是因为你的循规蹈矩,没有生活情趣,非常地乏味.现在,你是想讨论那个计划呢,还是这个计划呢?
Mike: Well Carol, that's because you live a very sad, uninteresting and boring life. Now do you want to talk about that or do you want to talk about this plan?
本:这个计划!
Ben: The plan!
开萝尔:耶.
Carol: Yeah.
迈克:好的,我去套爸爸,开萝尔,你两人去套妈妈.
Mike: Alright, ok now I'll work on dad and carol, you work on mom.
本:我去套谁?
Ben: Who do I work on?
迈克:你少吃点!
Mike: Losing weight.
迈克:爸爸,你有时间么,跟我唠会儿?
Mike: Dad, do you have a second to rap with me?
杰森:你想唠?
Jason: You want to rap?
迈克:对.可以么?
Mike: Yeah, is that the right word?
杰森:当然可以.3
Jason: Yeah sure if you're sammy davis jr.
迈克:谈话,聊天,
Mike: Nah nah you know what I mean.
就是随便说会儿话.爸爸,你的头发理得不错啊.
talk, chat, have one of our meaningful dialogues.Nice haircut by the way dad.
不不不,没别的意思,
Uhh no no, you know what I mean.
好不容易有这么一个机会,我们俩人能坐下来聊会儿.
just a chance for the two of us guys to get together to see how the
我就您这一个爸爸,不是么?而且,
heck we're doing.I mean you're my only dad right?
我是你仅有的三个孩子中的老大,是不是?
And I uh am one of your three only kids, aren't I?
杰森:你有什么样的麻烦了,迈克?
Jason: So what kind of trouble are you in Mike?
开萝尔:妈妈!
Carol: Mom!
麦琪:嗨,宝贝,什么事?
Maggie: Hi honey.What's up?
开萝尔:没事.
Carol: Nothing's up.why do you think something's up?
你为什么觉得有事呢?
I mean does there have to be something up just because I want to come
难道一定要有什么事我才会过来找您聊么?我想跟您一块出去,
in here and talk to you?
还想……
I mean I want to hang out with you and I want to ...
迈克:嗨,爸爸,你听说了么,我现在正在跟另外一个女孩约会呢?
Mike: So hey dad.Did you hear that I'm dating a new girl now?
杰森:迈克,你总在跟人约会,
Jason: Well mike you're always dating a new girl.
因为没有会第二次跟你出去.
Because nobody will go out with you twice.
迈克:不不不,爸爸,这会这个不一亲,她的名字是派图拉.
Mike: No no no, dad this one is special.Her name is Petula.
杰森:她不会是个美发师吧?
Jason: She wouldn't be a barber would she?
迈克:美发师?你为什么会问这个?
Mike: A barber?Why do you ask dad?Do you know any petula who's a barber?
难道你认识哪个叫派图拉的是美发师么?
One with, oh, say a mole painted on her face?
杰森:不,刚才本提到过派图拉.
Jason: No.Ben mentioned it.
迈克:哦,我明白了.
Mike: Oh I see.
杰森:迈克,你喜欢这样的谈话么?
Jason: Mike, are you enjoying this conversation?
迈克:还行.是这样的,
Mike: Ok um, alright here it is.
对您的社交生活,我有点疑问.
I'm having a little problem with my social life dad.
我觉得,像您这样的人肯定到处找人约会.
And I figured that a guy like you has probably dated around a lot.
杰森:没错,不过,那都是很长以前的事情了.
Jason: Yeah, well it was a long time ago but uh, yeah.
迈克:有时候您可能会固定一个或几个朋友,是么?
Mike: Yeah.You probably even went steady a time or two right?
杰森:对.
Jason: Yeah.
迈克:那,您可能跟其中的一些结婚,是么?
Mike: Heck, you probably even married a few of em right?
杰森:什么?
Jason: What?
开萝尔:你不知道么,离过婚的人大都不用收拾饭桌?
Carol: Did you know that most divorced people never have to set the table?
麦琪:什么?
Maggie: What?
开萝尔:大家不都知道么,她们都人猫在厨房里就着洗碗池吃饭.
Carol: Well it's a well known fact that they eat most meals hunched over a sink.
麦琪:哦,开萝尔.
Maggie: Oh carol.
开萝尔:如果你离过婚,你不会觉得这很有意思么?
Carol: You wouldn't think it was so funny if you were divorced.
麦琪:那它肯定会把我在厨房的时间节省很多.
Maggie: Well it sure would save me a lot of time in the kitchen.
开萝尔:顾左右而言它,逃避问题!
Carol: Well fine, duck the question!
麦琪:开萝尔,我逃避什么问题了?
Maggie: Carol, what question am I ducking?
开萝尔:妈妈,我还要怎么才能更明白点?但是,
Carol: Mom, how can I make it any clearer?
在餐桌上吃饭,会觉得怪怪的,是吧?
Bet it feels weird eating at the table, huh?
杰森:有一点倒是没有例外,就是,我的孩子一个个想不明白怎么回事.
Jason: Well that makes it unanimous.None of my children are making sense.
麦琪:告诉我什么原因,
Maggie: Tell me about it.
他们要么盯着我,好像我刚从死人堆里爬出来似的,
They're either staring at me like I'm back from the grave or telling me
要么跟我说些关于离过婚的人们的趣事.
interesting facts about divorced people.
麦琪:肯定有事.迈克也在一直问我,
Jason: Well there's something up.
问我结了多少次婚,
Mike was just asking me how many times I've been married and I ...
而我……等一等,他们知道了!
wait a minute.They know!Oh look!Just like I told you!
就你我以前跟你说过的!
They've been into everything down here.
他们什么都知道了.他们甚至知道我送你长袜的事.
They even found the stocking you gave me for the intern's comedy review.
麦琪:不是我的袜子.
Maggie: That's not mine.
杰森:肯定是这样.迈克,开萝尔,本.
Jason: Sure it is.Mike, carol, Ben.
麦琪:不,我穿的都是高的,这个短.
Maggie: No I wear tall.This is petite.
杰森:大家把手边的事放一放.好了,
Jason: We're getting off the subject here.
孩子们,你妈妈和我有话跟你们谈.
All right kids, your mom and I want to talk to you.
开萝尔:我肯定.
Carol: I'll bet!
迈克:我们听着呢.
Mike: We're listening.
麦琪:杰森,我来说.呣,我,呣……
Maggie: Jason, I'll handle this.Umm, I, um.
杰森:让我来说.
Jason: I'll handle it.
本:如果这还得磨蹭一会儿的话,那我想去叫份比萨.
Ben: If this is going to take a while, I'm going to call for a pizza.
杰森:给我坐下,本.是这样的,你妈妈和我是在1968年结的婚.
Jason: Sit down Ben.Now, your mother and I were married in 1968.
迈克:得了,爸爸,我们已经知道了,甚至于在1969年的时候你们还都没在一起生活.
Mike: Now c'mon dad we already know that weren't even living together in 1969.
杰森:对,没错.
Jason: Well yes.
开萝尔:我们还知道,你们都离过婚.
Carol: And we know you were divorced.
迈克:跟一个叫派图拉的人.
Mike: To somebody named Petula.
麦琪:谁?
Maggie: Who?
杰森:我不知道.
Jason: I don't know.
开萝尔:我们还知道,您也离过婚.
Carol: And we know that you got divorced too.
迈克:妈妈,不要否认,
Mike: Mom, don't try to deny that you were married to someone your dad
你跟一个被你的爸爸叫作呆子的人结过婚.
called a lunkhead.
麦琪:对.这个呆子就是你们的爸爸.
Maggie: That's right.The lunkhead's your dad.
杰森:谢谢你.
Jason: Thank you.
本:全都解释清楚了,我感觉好多了.
Ben: That explains it all.I feel much better.
迈克:不不,什么都没解释明白.
Mike: No no, that explains nothing.
麦琪:孩子们.这,这个很难解释.
Maggie: Kids.This is, this is difficult to explain.
你爸爸和我经历了一段很艰难的时期,其间我们曾认为,
But see your dad and I went through a period where we thought it was
两个人都拥有自己的事业,同时还要建立家庭,是不可能的.
impossible to have two careers and a marriage.
杰森:的确如此.我在菲尼克斯实习,而你们的妈妈在上班.
Jason: It was.I was doing my internship in phoenix and your mom had the new job at Newsweek.
麦琪:对,所以我们,
Maggie: Yeah, and so we, we split up.
我们分手了.如果你的生活,工作有既定的目标的话,
Well when you spend your life living working for a goal,
就那么放弃,是非常难的.
it's hard to give it up just like that.
杰森:是不可能的.
Jason: Impossible
麦琪:所以我们分道扬镳了,那是我一生中最暗淡无光的日子.
Maggie: So we went our separate ways.It was the worst time of my life.
杰森:我也一样.我们什么事都谈不拢.
Jason: Me too.See, we didn't disagree about anything.
实际上,事情已经闹到了这个地步,
In fact, it got so at one point my lawyer stood up in court and he
我的律师在法庭上就跳了起来,
blurted out well why don't you just save everybody a lot of trouble and
脱口而出----为什么你就不能不离,给我们大家都省省心.
stay married!
麦琪:于是,我们四目以对,一刹那间觉得我们从前好傻啊.
Maggie: Well we looked at each other and realized that at once how stupid we'd been.
杰森:同时,在那一刹那间,知道了真正重要的是什么.
Jason: As well as what was really important.
麦琪:于是,离婚就永远没能进行到底.
Maggie: And the divorce never went through.
杰森:多谢上帝.
Jason: Thank god
迈克:很好,那请您解释一下,这个宝贝儿是谁.
Mike: Alright, well then explain who this babe is.
杰森:她是派图拉*克拉科,是60年代很红的歌手,
Jason: Well this babe is Petula Clark.
我那时是她的歌迷俱乐部的成员,不,是会长,
She was a popular singer in the 60's and I was a member of her fan
不过,时间不长.
club.Ok, president.For a very short time ok.
迈克:我早就跟你说过了,没什么可担心的.
Mike: See, I told you there was nothing to worry about.
开萝尔:那,你以前怎么不告诉我们?
Carol: Well why didn't you tell us this before?
杰森:其实,我们不是有意要把这事瞒着你们的,
Jason: Well we weren't trying to keep this a secret on purpose.
我们是在等待一个合适的机会,等你们足够大,
It's just that we were waiting for you to be old enough and then by the
可是,
time you were Ben came along.
刚巧那时生了本.又过了一段时间,
And after a while it just seemed the whole thing was ancient history.
整个事情好像是尘封的历史,不再重要了.
It really didn't matter at all.
麦琪:重要的是我们彼此相爱有多深,以及,
Maggie: What matters is how much we love each other and you.Each of you.
你们.你们中的每一个.过去17年里的日日夜夜.
Everyday of the last 17 years.
杰森:我觉得,正是因为我们那次几乎铸成大错,
Jason: And I like to think that it's because we came so close to making
所以在过去的17年里才会如此的甜蜜.
a mistake like that the last 17 have been so good.
麦琪:那次让我们学会了微妙的艺术,妥协.
Maggie: It made us learn the fine art of compromise.
而且,
And we care enough to give each other a little room and the right to his
我们会足够谨慎,以留给彼此一些余地及申述自己观点的权利.
own point of view.
杰森:正如我在婚礼上所说的,
Jason: And like I said at the wedding.
你是我今生唯一要娶的女人.
You're the only woman I ever wanted to marry.
开萝尔:那就是说,你没有说谎了.
Carol: So the toast wasn't a lie.
杰森:没有.
Jason: No.
本:那就是说,你们分手,就是为了摆脱爱的折磨?
Ben: So you guys split up just to get it out of the way?
杰森:我自己决不可能说的如此贴切,本.
Jason: I couldn't have said it any better myself Ben.
本:哇,我有了一个动人的家庭故事,
Ben: Wow, I'm gonna have a family history that's going to make Stinky
肯定会让斯汀金*萨利汶羡慕的.
Sullivan smell.
开萝尔:我觉得,这是我听到过的,
Carol: Well, I just think that that is just the most beautiful,
最美丽动人,最浪漫温馨的故事.
most romantic, thing I have ever: heard.God bless you.
迈克:我早就告诉过他们,他们想得太多了.
Mike: Look, I told them they were getting carried away.
杰森:肯定的.
Jason: Sure.
杰森:请允许我代表我们三个说一声,
Mike: And I speak for all of us when I say that I am really glad
我们非常高兴您俩位重归于好.
you guys got back together when you did.
迈克:真好,迈克.
Maggie: So sweet Mike.
迈克:是啊,如果你真的再多等一年,那我就不是我了,就成了开萝尔了!
Mike: Yeah, if you had waited one more year I'd have been carol.
杰森:玛丽亚.
Jason: Maria Flaggenhoffer.
麦琪:对不起,你说什么?
Maggie: Excuse me
杰森:我刚刚记起来,玛丽亚,
Jason: Yeah, I just remembered, Maria Flaggenhoffer.
我的连衣裤是她给的.
That's who gave me the panty hose.She's a proctologist.Now.
麦琪:亲爱的,我不会吃醋的.
Maggie: Fine.Honey, I'm not jealous.
杰森:好的.我想告诉你我是从哪儿得到这些东西的,
Jason: Well alright.I just wanted you to know where I got them just in case.
以防万一.还有段故事呢,很美的故事.
It's a pretty good story though.
麦琪:我不感兴趣.
Maggie: I don't care.
杰森:真的?
Jason: No?
麦琪:真的不感兴趣,尤其是我看到他的大腿有赘肉.
Maggie: No, particularly when I see that she was a bit thick in the thigh.
杰森:哦,不,
Jason: Oh no, not maria, she was ...
我说的不是玛丽亚,她是……她超重了大概15磅.我刚才说什么了?
uh well yeah she was 15 pounds overweight .
25磅,可能还不止.
what am I saying?25 pounds if she was lucky.
麦琪:杰森!过去的已经过去了.
Maggie: Jason!What's passed has passed.
杰森:对.
Jason: Good, yes.
麦琪:从照片看来,她看起来人不错.
Maggie: And from the look of her picture she looks like a nice person.
杰森:哦,对,她是不错.
Jason: Oh yeah she was.
麦琪:很有情趣的女人,我觉得?
Maggie: A fun lady I guess.
杰森:哦,对,
Jason: Oh yeah, she had a great sense of humor hahahaha yeah,
她非常有幽默感;她还非常爱笑.
she loved to laugh.
麦琪:那我肯定,你也给过她不少的笑容喽.
Maggie: And you gave her plenty to laugh at I'll bet.
杰森:啊---麦琪.
Jason: Ahhh Maggie.
麦琪:哦,你胆子可真不小啊.
Maggie: Oh you've got a lot of nerve.
杰森:麦琪!好了,别闹了,她超重,得多35磅.
麦琪:肯定的啊.
00:23:07,500
Jason: Maggie!Oh c'mon she was 35 pounds overweight. Maggie: Sure.